the forecast is calling for a wet one
today what's up everybody it's jake
coming at you from a rainy barbie garage
gym and today
i've got a cold plunge with me ice ice
baby if vanilla ice was able to look
into the future when he ripped off david
bowie off his one hit then he must have
been thinking about the plunge cold
plunge not only can this thing offer
temperatures low enough to speed up
recovery it may also even lead to mental
clarity and boost your immune system if
you're anything like me
recovery after a long day is a must no
matter what it be from running lifting
even just a long day in general you've
got to have it
so in this video i'm going to hop in
this cold plunge go over all the details
it has
features the price some pros and cons
and also who should buy it and maybe who
shouldn't buy it
now before i literally hop into this
cold plunge we have reviewed a ton of
cold plunges on barbin.com if you want
to find our best list just google barbin
best cold plunges you'll find our best
list and find out where this one lands
on it
all right there's a lot i like about
this cold plunge so try to take some
notes if you can i think personally this
is one of the best looking options on
the market if not the best looking
option coming from somebody who used to
take a ton of ice bats back in my
football days it looks way better than
the tin cans we were having to use back
then thanks to the motor on the side of
the plunge the temperature will stay at
39 degrees all day if you want it to
meaning there's no more need for ice no
more need for prepping your tub
whatsoever it'll stay there all day
thanks to the cover and on the flip side
some of these models even offer hot
water so you can transform your tub into
a hot tub with temperatures reaching 103
degrees fahrenheit
also located on the side is a filtration
system that in the words of andre 3000
will keep this thing so fresh and so
clean for up to six months without ever
needing to change the water and thanks
to the acrylic build this thing is an
absolute beast it could last you years
potentially even a lifetime even if you
keep it outdoors like we have it right
now
all right now with all that being said
there are a few potential cons you may
run into when buying this luxury item
you have to be prepared to spend a chunk
of change because that's essentially
what this is if you head over to their
website you will notice that it's a
shade under 5 000
and that might fall out of your price
range if that's the case then you can
always opt for a regular old ice bath
but
on the flip side you will have to prep
the water you will have to put ice in
and the plunge completely eliminates all
of that for you and also don't get me
wrong you're gonna find out today just
how cold this thing is 39 degrees is
very frigid but it might not be as cold
as a regular old-fashioned ice bath
all right now let's plunge into the
pricing on the plunge if you head over
to their website you will notice a price
difference between the options that do
feature hot water and the ones that do
not feature hot water this video this
model does not feature hot water you'll
find the pricing for this one just under
five thousand dollars but if you wanted
the hot water you'll see that price jump
up to fifty five hundred dollars and
personally my opinion if you're already
spending five thousand dollars on
something why not spend an extra 500 to
get that hot water all right with that
being said there are other models
available for you to purchase on their
website the pro model features a cold
water and a hot water option with a
motor three times the power of this base
model you can find the pro model of the
cold water option at six thousand
dollars while the pro hot and cold
option is sixty five hundred dollars
there is also an excel option the
regular cold version of the xl is listed
at seven thousand dollars while the hot
and cold xl is seventy five hundred
dollars don't worry i'll talk to you
about all the dimensions of that later
and what makes it in xl
lastly there is a commercial option
available in the xl size and standard
size this features a more robust pump
with a one-year commercial warranty
standard size is 6 500 while the xl is 7
so wrapping things up with price this
base model finds itself towards the
higher end of things compared to the
rest of the market but at the end of the
day it is a luxury item you don't have
to do any prep work whatsoever zero ice
which i think justifies the price all
right so this cold plunge is made with
acrylic material which weighs 150 pounds
when it's empty and upwards to a
thousand pounds when it's full but this
base model is five and a half feet long
two feet tall and three and a half feet
wide but on the other hand if you're
gonna get the xl you'd find those
dimensions expand to eleven and a half
feet long five feet tall and five feet
wide
so for reference the base model of the
plunge is about the size of your
standard bathtub but you still could
come into the problem of a spacing issue
and if that does happen for you you may
need to find a smaller alternative now
let's dig into some of these accessories
that do come with your colt plunge it
features an insulated cover as well as
how-to videos on how to properly cold
plunge as well as a cell phone holder
that clamps directly to the side of the
tub and a 20 micron filter that's really
ideal for any large debris and make sure
that your water stays crystal clear
throughout your usage also you do have
underwater light in case you want to
plunge while it's dark outside
you also have the option to purchase a
six month water maintenance package on
the plunge website for 190 this package
includes six filters a 16 ounce box with
spa sanitizer a 32 ounce bakla spa
oxidizer a 16 ounce alkalinity up and a
16 ounce ph down as well as 25 testing
strips so this ozone enriched water is
not only easier on the skin but also
kills microbes as effectively as
chlorine does
all right now let's walk you through
some of the details of this cold plunge
as you can see you do have your
insulated cover right here this will
really allow that temperature to stay
exactly where you have it set 24 7 365
that's not going to change on you
whatsoever also it's that nice acrylic
build
meaning it'll go anywhere you can put it
outside if you want it's able to
withstand those harsh elements now if
you come around back right here and if
you ever need to drain the tub for
whatever reason simply lift up on this
cover
and the drain will be exposed all you
got to do give this thing a nice twist
right here water flows out nice and easy
for you since i got you here this is
also where your filter is located so if
you ever do need to change it one gets
nasty for whatever reason simply unscrew
this one pop a new one in really simply
done all right so if i bring you around
back over here you'll see that this
really is a true plug and plunge cold
plunge
really all you have to do is connect
your pipes and make sure you find your
power source
toss in the hose
let it fill up and this guy will take
care of everything else on its own so as
you can see ours is at 40 degrees right
now well we want this guy down to 39
which is the coldest temperature so
we're going to press set
make sure that this set is at 39 with
the arrows press set again
and it'll eventually kick in and start
bringing that temperature down since
this is the base model you can expect
that temperature to drop around two and
a half degrees per hour but if you were
to upgrade to the pro that's gonna be
around eight to ten degrees per hour
let's do it
that's cold
all right everybody as you can see i'm
officially in the cold plunge right now
and
in case you're wondering yeah it's it's
pretty cold uh it's at the lowest
setting 39 degrees as you can see i've
got plenty of room i'm around 5 10 or so
um take that on a good day
but yeah i mean i got plenty of room my
legs are fully extended
completely
eliminating any chance of a heat pocket
being formed underneath my legs
allowing to get full effect from this
cold plunge
and yeah we're just gonna sit here for a
little bit and
take it minute by minute as long as i
can handle it
[Music]
all right so who should buy the cold
plunge well if you're an athlete or
maybe you just want to focus on your
recovery this is a great option to
incorporate that into your routine and
if you do plunge often you'll love the
fact that you don't have to do anything
to your water no more adding extra water
no more adding ice to keep it at a cold
temperature it will stay at whatever you
have it set at and third you can use it
outside thanks to the insulated cover
the filtration system and the skimmer
net it'll make sure your water stays
crystal clear okay so then who should
not buy the cold plunge well really it
just comes down to two things price and
available space yes this is a luxury
item and it is a little bit on the high
end of things so if it falls out of your
budget then you may want to consider a
cheaper option but that cheaper option
may have less amenities and may not be
as convenient as the cold plunge and two
space this base model is around the size
of a standard bathtub so that's
something you need to consider before
you make your purchase if you don't have
the adequate space for it then you might
want to consider a smaller option all
right well that's all she wrote for the
plunge cold plunge yes this is a sleek
design and it is a really easy way to
incorporate plunging into your daily
routine but at the same time it is a bit
pricey and it does dominate a good
amount of space which are two things you
really need to consider before
purchasing if you want to find out more
about this product and any other cold
plungers out there head over to barband
check out our best list and you can find
out more
[Music]